Guide to the Jewish Labor Committee Records, Part II WAG.025.002
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Jewish Labor Committee Records, Part II
1948-1956
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Jewish Labor Committee (U.S.)
WAG.025.002
150 Linear Feet (150 boxes)
The Jewish Labor Committee, an umbrella group of Jewish trade unions and fraternal organizations, was founded in 1934 for the purpose of organizing opposition to Fascism, providing assistance to its victims, and fighting all forms of bigotry. After the Second World War the Committee continued its program of relief to Holocaust victims, providing shipments of food, clothing, and medical supplies. It also provided immigration assistance, and offered help with employment and housing for refugees who came to the United States. The JLC's Holocaust-related records, Part II (1948-1956), include minutes, convention proceedings, reports, press releases, correspondence, survivors' biographical files and a wide range of printed material. Documented in detail are the JLC's efforts to sustain and resettle survivors, contacts with socialist and trade-union leaders in post-war Europe, proposals for liberalizing American immigration policy, lobbying for reparations, and anti-discrimination work.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The first shipment of records was donated by the Jewish Labor Committee in 1984. The accession numbers associated with these donations are 1984.002 and 1984.006. A number of addition donations to the collection have been made by the JLC and its individual members over the years.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
The Jewish Labor Committee, an umbrella group of Jewish trade unions and fraternal organizations, was founded in 1934 for the purpose of organizing opposition to Fascism, providing assistance to its victims, and fighting all forms of bigotry. It maintained close contact with European resistance movements and was able to effect the rescue of several thousand labor and socialist activists and their families.
After the Second World War the Committee continued its program of relief to Holocaust victims, providing massive shipments of food, clothing, and medical supplies. It cooperated with other Jewish agencies in reuniting families, provided immigration assistance, offered help with employment and housing for refugees who came to the United States, and had several representatives working in the Displaced Persons camps in Germany.
The Committee organized a post-war "Child Adoption Program" through which American trade unions, branches of fraternal organizations such as the Workmen's Circle and others made monthly financial contributions toward the support of thousands of destitute children in Europe and elsewhere. The Jewish Labor Committee was the main source of financial support for a number of children's homes in France, Italy, Belgium, Poland and Palestine/Israel. An eighteen-minute film about the children's homes in France, commissioned by the JLC, was an effective fund-raising tool (this film is available for viewing at the Library). The Committee also made substantial contributions to the reconstruction of Jewish culture after 1945 by financing Yiddish libraries, schools and publications in North and South America, Europe and Palestine/Israel.
The JLC sent emissaries to assess the situation in the ruined Jewish communities and refugee camps of Europe beginning in 1945. Their reports, and those of survivors who toured the U.S. under JLC auspices, brought the harsh realities of the aftermath of the Holocaust to American audiences. Officers of the JLC were active in the lobbying effort that secured reparations for victims of the Holocaust from the governments of Germany and Austria in the early 1950s.
Scope and Content Note
The Jewish Labor Committee (U.S.) Records as a whole have been divided into three parts, each of which has been processed separately: Part I: Holocaust-Era Files, 1934-1947 (microfilmed); Part II: Holocaust-Era Files, 1948-1956, mostly documenting rescue and relief work and overseas political contacts (microfilmed); and Part III: Administrative Files, 1957-1990s, and Anti-Discrimination Department Files, 1943-1960s (not microfilmed), documenting organizational activities in general from the late 1950s to the 1990s, and domestic anti-discrimination activities from the mid-1940s through the 1990s.
This finding aid describes the Jewish Labor Committee (U.S.) Records, Part II only. The JLC's Holocaust-related records for 1948-1956 include minutes, convention proceedings, reports, press releases, correspondence, survivors' biographical files, financial records and a wide range of printed material. Documented in detail are the JLC's efforts to sustain and resettle victims of the Holocaust, continuing contacts with socialist and trade-union leaders in post-War Europe, campaigns against Communism in the U.S. and on behalf of the rights of Soviet Jewry, and proposals for liberalizing U.S. immigration policy. Also included is a small amount of general material documenting the JLC's anti-discrimination work.
Part II is divided into four series, with a number of sub-series. A considerable amount of correspondence and many reports, flyers, clippings and other documents are in Yiddish.
Series I: Administrative and Organizational Records, is comprised of a constitution, minutes, convention records, incoming and outgoing correspondence of JLC officers and staff (including Lasar Epstein, Samuel Estrin, Joseph Godson, Adolph Held, Walter Kirschenbaum, Emanuel Muravchik and Jacob Pat), general subject files, division records and clippings scrapbooks. (NOTE: The JLC's Women's Division was founded in 1947 and the Workmen's Circle Division in 1946; the few early files for those groups have been included in this series to avoid dividing the record of their activity between Parts I and II.)
Series II: American Cities, is comprised of incoming and outgoing correspondence, as well as clippings and notices, documenting JLC activity and contacts in U.S. cities and towns. The files are arranged alphabetically by state, and by town or city within each state.
Series III: Foreign Countries, is comprised of incoming and outgoing correspondence (much of it in Yiddish) with survivors, refugees, political sympathizers and others in many countries. Canadian files document activity of JLC branches in that country. The files for France, Poland, Italy, Sweden and Israel contain a good deal of correspondence relating to JLC aid efforts directed at East European survivors in those countries. The files for Germany are largely devoted to correspondence with two JLC representatives in the Displaced Persons camps, Nathan Gierowitz and Bella Meiksin.
Series IV: Immigration, Resettlement and Refugee Aid, is comprised of files relating to location of surviving relatives, procurement of visas, aid to child survivors in Europe and Israel, and efforts to secure reparations for survivors from the German and Austrian governments. Sub-series D and E are made up of biographical files of child survivors (mostly in France and Italy) and card-files of biographical information on survivors in DP camps. Sub-series F consists of JLC financial ledgers, with entries for expenditures on both foreign and domestic aid to refugees, among other expenses and receipts. (NOTE: Sub-series F was transferred after filming for Part I was completed, it therefore contains records from 1934-1949 records.)
Arrangement
All series are arranged alphabetically by topic or personal name, except for Series I, Sub-series A, B, D and H (Minutes, Convention and National Conference Records, Meetings-Events, and Scrapbooks), and Series IV, F (Financial Ledgers), which are arranged chronologically.
This portion of the Jewish Labor Committee (U.S.) collection is organized into four series, with subseries, as follows:
I. Administrative and Organizational Records
A. Constitution and Minutes
B. Convention and National Conference Records
C. Correspondence
1. General
2. Individuals
3. Other Organizations
D. Meetings, Conferences and Other Events
E. General Files
F. Women's Division Records, 1947-1956
G. Workmen's Circle Division Records, 1946-1956
H. Scrapbooks, 1949-1956
II. American Cities
III. Foreign Countries
IV. Immigration, Resettlement and Refugee Aid
A. Immigration and Aid
B. German-Austrian Reparations Files
C. Child Adoption Program
D. Child Adoption Case Files
E. Displaced Persons Card Files
F. JLC Financial Ledgers, 1934-1949
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Due to the fragile nature of the original materials, researchers must use the microfilmed version; microfilm call number is R-7015.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
The following Jewish Labor Committee materials are located at this repository:
Jewish Labor Committee (U.S.) Records, Part I (WAG 025.001)
Jewish Labor Committee (U.S.) Records, Part II (WAG 025.002)
Jewish Labor Committee, Boston Records (WAG 159)
Jewish Labor Committee, Chicago Records (WAG 160)
Jewish Labor Committee (U.S.) Oral History Collection (OH 027)
Jewish Labor Committee (U.S.) Photograph Collection (PHOTOS 048)
Jewish Labor Committee Ephemera (EPHEMERA 003)
Issues of the JLC Review
Issues of JLC Outlook
Issues of the JLC Civil Rights Newsletter
JLC Biennial Convention Journals
The following related archival collections are also located at the Tamiment Library:
Ad Hoc Committee on the Human Rights and Genocide Treaties Records (WAG 037)
Julius Bernstein Papers (WAG 116)
Edward S. Goldstein: Jewish Labor Committee Research Files (WAG 232)
Isaiah Minkoff Papers (WAG 086)
Jacob Pat Papers (WAG 127)
Baruch Charney Vladeck Papers (TAM 037)
The records of the National Conference on Soviet Jewry and the National Jewish Community Relations Advisory Council are located at the Center for Jewish History's American Jewish Historical Society in New York City.
Separated Material
During the processing work that occurred after 1985 through 2012, some materials from the Jewish Labor Committee Records were separated to other Tamiment Library collections. Photographs and other graphic material were separated to the partially processed Jewish Labor Committee (U.S.) Photographs (PHOTOS 048). Posters, artwork, artifacts, and other ephemera were separated to the unprocessed Jewish Labor Committee Ephemera (EPHEMERA 003) collection.
Also during this period, certain materials were separated to external institutions. A portion of materials from the JLC Records at the Tamiment Library were donated to the Center for Jewish History's American Jewish Historical Society in 1997. Throughout the 1990s, Tamiment donated approximately 300 audio tapes, mostly recordings of the JLC's radio broadcasts or of various JLC events, to the Center for Jewish History's YIVO Institute for Jewish Research. In 2009, Tamiment also donated to YIVO approximately 4 linear feet of Yiddish transcripts of the JLC's radio program, as well as family photographs of Martin Lapan, former Executive Director of the JLC. Eight volumes of Holocaust survivor lists, which were duplicated in the JLC records at Tamiment, were donated to the Museum of Jewish Heritage in 1990.
New York (N.Y.).; Italy; Holocaust, Jewish (1939-1945); Refugee camps.; Nazi concentration camps; France -- History -- 20th century; Poland |x History |y 1918-1945.; Sweden |x History |y 20th century.; Jewish refugees.; Canada.; World War, 1939-1945 -- Jews -- Rescue.; Reports.; Germany.; France.; Israel.; Scrapbooks.; Newsletters.; Minutes (administrative records); Correspondence.; Jewish labor unions.; Card files.; Ledgers (account books); Sweden.; Poland; Jewish Labor Committee (U.S.); Held, Adolph, 1885-1969; Gierowitz, Nathan; Epstein, Lasar; American Jewish Joint Distribution Committee; Pat, Jacob, 1890-1966; Meiksin, Bella; Muravchik, Emanuel; Jewish Labour Committee (Canada); Kirschenbaum, Walter; Jewish Labor Committee (U.S.)
- Series I: Administrative and Organizational Records
  - Subseries I:A: Constitution and Minutes
    - Constitution, 1949 (Box 54, Folder 1)
      General note
      Microfilm reel#: 169
    - By-Laws, 1953 (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - Minutes: Administrative Committee, 1948 (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Minutes: Administrative Committee, 1949 (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Minutes: Administrative Committee, 1950 (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - Minutes: Administrative Committee, 1951 (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - Minutes: Administrative Committee, 1952 (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - Minutes: Administrative Committee, 1953 (Box 54, Folder 8)
    - Minutes: Administrative Committee, 1954 (Box 54, Folder 9)
    - Minutes: Administrative Committee, 1955 (Box 54, Folder 10)
    - Minutes: Administrative Committee, 1956 (Box 54, Folder 11)
    - Minutes: Executive Committee, 1949-1955 (Box 54, Folder 12)
    - Minutes: Executive Staff Meetings, 1955-1956 (Box 54, Folder 13)
    - Minutes: Office Committee, 1948-1949 (Box 54, Folder 14)
    - Minutes: Office Committee, 1950-1956 (Box 54, Folder 15)
      Microfilm reel#: 170
  - Subseries I:B: Convention and National Conference Records
    - National Convention: Preparations, 1949 (Box 54, Folder 16)
    - National Convention: Greetings, 1949 (Box 54, Folder 17)
    - National Convention: I, 1949 (Box 54, Folder 18)
    - [note: there is no folder 19], undated (Box 54, Folder 19)
    - National Convention: II, 1949 (Box 54, Folder 20)
    - National Convention: Publicity, 1949 (Box 54, Folder 21)
    - Executive Committee Conference, Jun 30, 1949 (Box 54, Folder 22)
    - National Executive Committee Conference, 1950 (Box 54, Folder 23)
    - National Executive Committee Conference: I, 1951 (Box 54, Folder 24)
    - National Executive Committee Conference: II, 1951 (Box 54, Folder 25)
    - National Executive Committee Conference: III, 1951 (Box 54, Folder 26)
      Microfilm reel#: 171
    - National Convention: Preparations, 1953 (Box 54, Folder 27)
    - National Convention: Greetings, 1953 (Box 54, Folder 28)
    - National Convention: Speeches and Reports, 1953 (Box 54, Folder 29)
    - National Convention: Resolutions, 1953 (Box 54, Folder 30)
    - National Convention: Preparations, 1955 (Box 54, Folder 31)
    - National Convention: Speeches and Reports, 1955 (Box 54, Folder 32)
    - National Convention: Resolutions, 1955 (Box 54, Folder 33)
    - National Convention: Adolph Held 70th Birthday, 1955 (Box 54, Folder 34)
  - Subseries I:C: Correspondence
    - General
      - Correspondence: General, 1948 (Box 55, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence: General, Jan 1949-May 1949 (Box 55, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence: General, Jun 1949-Dec 1949 (Box 55, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence: General, 1950-1956 (Box 55, Folder 4)
        Microfilm reel#: 172
      - Telegrams, 1955-1956 (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - Individuals.
      - Brumberg, Joseph, 1948-1952 (Box 55, Folder 6)
      - Chanin, Herschell, 1950 (Box 55, Folder 7)
      - Chanin, Nathan (Nachum), 1948-1956 (Box 55, Folder 8)
      - Epstein, Lasar, 1948 (Box 55, Folder 9)
      - Epstein, Lasar, 1949 (Box 55, Folder 10)
      - Epstein, Lasar, 1950-1951 (Box 55, Folder 11)
      - Epstein, Lasar, 1952 (Box 55, Folder 12)
      - Epstein, Lasar, 1953 (Box 55, Folder 13)
        Microfilm reel#: 173
      - Epstein, Lasar, 1954 (Box 55, Folder 14)
      - Epstein, Lasar, 1955 (Box 55, Folder 15)
      - Epstein, Lasar, 1956 (Box 55, Folder 16)
      - Estrin, Samuel, 1948 (Box 55, Folder 17)
      - Estrin, Samuel, 1949-1956 (Box 55, Folder 18)
      - Estrin, Samuel (European Tour), 1952 (Box 55, Folder 19)
      - Godson, Joseph, 1948 (Box 55, Folder 20)
      - Godson, Joseph, 1949-1950 (Box 55, Folder 21)
      - Goldman, Paul, 1948-1956 (Box 55, Folder 22)
      - Held, Adolph, 1948-1949 (Box 56, Folder 1)
        Microfilm reel#: 174
      - Held, Adolph, 1950-1951 (Box 56, Folder 2)
      - Held, Adolph, Jan 1952-Sep 1952 (Box 56, Folder 3)
      - Held, Adolph, Oct 1952-Dec 1952 (Box 56, Folder 4)
      - Held, Adolph, 1953 (Box 56, Folder 5)
      - Held, Adolph, 1954-1955 (Box 56, Folder 6)
      - Held, Adolph, 1954-1955 (Box 56, Folder 7)
      - Held, Adolph, 1956 (Box 56, Folder 8)
      - Heller, Philip, 1956 (Box 56, Folder 9)
      - Kaye, Betty, 1950-1955 (Box 56, Folder 10)
      - Kaye, Betty, 1956 (Box 56, Folder 11)
      - Kirschenbaum, Walter, 1949-May 1952 (Box 56, Folder 12)
        Microfilm reel#: 175
      - Kirschenbaum, Walter, Jun 1952-Dec 1952 (Box 56, Folder 13)
      - Kirschenbaum, Walter, 1953 (Box 56, Folder 14)
      - Kirschenbaum, Walter, 1954 (Box 56, Folder 15)
      - Kirschenbaum, Walter, 1955 (Box 56, Folder 16)
      - Kirschenbaum, Walter, 1956 (Box 56, Folder 17)
      - Kissman, Joseph, 1948-1950 (Box 56, Folder 18)
        Microfilm reel#: 176
      - Kissman, Joseph, 1951-1956 (Box 56, Folder 19)
      - Muravchik, Emanuel, 1948 (Box 57, Folder 1)
      - Muravchik, Emanuel, Jan 1949-Aug 1949 (Box 57, Folder 2)
      - Muravchik, Emanuel, Sep 1949-Dec 1949 (Box 57, Folder 3)
      - Muravchik, Emanuel, 1950-1951 (Box 57, Folder 4)
      - Muravchik, Emanuel, 1952 (Box 57, Folder 5)
      - Muravchik, Emanuel, 1953-1955 (Box 57, Folder 6)
      - Muravchik, Emanuel, 1956 (Box 57, Folder 7)
      - Pat, Jacob, 1948 (Box 57, Folder 8)
      - Pat, Jacob, 1949 (Box 57, Folder 9)
        Microfilm reel#: 177
      - Pat, Jacob, 1950-1951 (Box 57, Folder 10)
      - Pat, Jacob, 1952 (Box 57, Folder 11)
      - Pat, Jacob, 1953 (Box 57, Folder 12)
      - Pat, Jacob, 1954 (Box 57, Folder 13)
      - Pat, Jacob, 1955 (Box 57, Folder 14)
      - Pat, Jacob, 1956 (Box 57, Folder 15)
      - Pat, J.: Book, Ashes and Fire, 1948 (Box 57, Folder 16)
        Microfilm reel#: 178
      - Pat, Jacob: European Tour, 1949 (Box 57, Folder 17)
      - Pat, Jacob: South American Tour, 1948 (Box 57, Folder 18)
      - Pat, Jacob: Speeches/Articles, 1948, 1950 (Box 57, Folder 19)
      - Patt, Emanuel, 1948-1954 (Box 57, Folder 20)
      - Robbins, Edward: Fundraising, 1948 (Box 57, Folder 21)
      - Salert, Irving, 1948-1952 (Box 57, Folder 22)
      - Salert, Irving: Memos, 1949 (Box 57, Folder 23)
      - Schlitt, Jacob, 1956 (Box 57, Folder 24)
      - Silver, George, 1949-1956 (Box 57, Folder 25)
      - Stern, Will, 1948, 1956 (Box 57, Folder 26)
      - Tabachinsky, Benjamin, undated (Box 58, Folder 1)
      - Tabachinsky, Benjamin, undated (Box 58, Folder 2)
      - Tabachinsky, Benjamin, 1948 (Box 58, Folder 3)
      - Tabachinsky, Benjamin, 1949 (Box 58, Folder 4)
      - Tabachinsky, Benjamin, 1950 (Box 58, Folder 5)
      - Tabachinsky, Benjamin, 1951 (Box 58, Folder 6)
        Microfilm reel#: 179
      - Tabachinsky, Benjamin, 1952 (Box 58, Folder 7)
      - Tabachinsky, Benjamin, 1953 (Box 58, Folder 8)
      - Tabachinsky, Benjamin, 1954 (Box 58, Folder 9)
      - Tabachinsky, Benjamin, 1955 (Box 58, Folder 10)
      - Tabachinsky, Benjamin, 1956 (Box 58, Folder 11)
    - Other Organizations
      - ADL-AJC-JLC Policy and Program Committee, 1951-1952 (Box 58, Folder 12)
      - American Association for a Democratic Germany, 1949 (Box 58, Folder 13)
      - American Association for the United Nations, 1948-1952 (Box 58, Folder 14)
      - American Committee on United Europe, 1951-1953 (Box 58, Folder 15)
      - American Council for Judaism, 1950 (Box 58, Folder 16)
      - American Federation for Polish Jews, 1948 (Box 58, Folder 17)
      - American Federation of Jews from Central Europe, 1949 (Box 58, Folder 18)
      - American Federation of Labor, 1948-1950 (Box 58, Folder 19)
        Microfilm reel#: 180
      - American Federation of Labor (and AFL-CIO), 1951-1956 (Box 58, Folder 20)
      - American Friends Service Committee, 1953 (Box 58, Folder 21)
      - American Financial and Development Corporation for Israel, 1951-1952 (Box 58, Folder 22)
      - American Friends of the Captive Nations, 1956 (Box 58, Folder 23)
      - American Jewish Committee, 1948-1956 (Box 58, Folder 24)
      - American Jewish Congress, 1949-1956 (Box 58, Folder 25)
      - American Jewish Joint Distribution Committee, 1948-1956 (Box 58, Folder 26)
      - American Jewish Labor Council, 1948 (Box 58, Folder 27)
      - American Jewish League Against Communism, 1955 (Box 58, Folder 28)
      - American Jewish Tercentenary Committee, 1952-1953 (Box 58, Folder 29)
      - American Labor Education Service, 1948-1954 (Box 58, Folder 30)
      - American Labor Research Institute, 1948 (Box 58, Folder 31)
      - American Memorial to Six Million Jews of Europe, 1948 (Box 58, Folder 32)
      - American ORT Federation, 1948-1956 (Box 58, Folder 33)
      - American Red Cross, 1948-1949 (Box 58, Folder 34)
      - American Red Magen Dovid for Israel, 1949-1951 (Box 58, Folder 35)
      - American Red Magen Dovid for Palestine, 1948 (Box 58, Folder 36)
      - American Youth for Political Action, 1949 (Box 58, Folder 37)
      - American Zionist Council, 1950-1951 (Box 59, Folder 1)
        Microfilm reel#: 181
      - American Zionist Council, 1952-1956 (Box 59, Folder 2)
      - Association of Jewish Writers and Journalists Refugees from Poland, 1948-1950 (Box 59, Folder 3)
      - Atran Foundation, 1952-1956 (Box 59, Folder 4)
      - Axis Victims League, 1951 (Box 59, Folder 5)
      - Bialystoker Organizations, 1948-1953 (Box 59, Folder 6)
      - B'nai B'rith, 1948-1952 (Box 59, Folder 7)
      - CARE, 1949 (Box 59, Folder 8)
      - Central Yiddish Cultural Organization (CYCO), 1948-1956 (Box 59, Folder 9)
      - CYCO: Froyen Centrale, 1952-1953 (Box 59, Folder 10)
      - Common Council for American Unity, 1949, 1952 (Box 59, Folder 11)
      - Conference on Jewish Relations, 1951 (Box 59, Folder 12)
      - Congress for Jewish Culture, 1949-1950 (Box 59, Folder 13)
      - Congress for Jewish Culture, 1951-1956 (Box 59, Folder 14)
      - Congress of Industrial Organizations, 1948-1955 (Box 59, Folder 15)
      - Council against Communist Aggression, 1955-1958 (Box 59, Folder 16)
      - Council of Jewish Federations and Welfare Funds, 1948-1953 (Box 59, Folder 17)
      - Council of Jewish Federations and Welfare Funds, 1954-1956 (Box 59, Folder 18)
      - Economic Cooperation Administration, 1949 (Box 59, Folder 19)
      - Farband Housing Corporation, 1955 (Box 59, Folder 20)
        Microfilm reel#: 182
      - Free Jewish Club, 1949-1952 (Box 59, Folder 21)
      - Freeland League, 1949-1952 (Box 59, Folder 22)
      - Friends of Austrian Labor, 1948-1950 (Box 59, Folder 23)
      - HIAS, 1948-1956 (Box 59, Folder 24)
      - Histadrut, 1949 (Box 59, Folder 25)
      - Institute for Social Research, 1952 (Box 59, Folder 26)
      - International Confederation of Free Trade Unions, 1951-1956 (Box 59, Folder 27)
      - International Federation of Free Journalists, 1951 (Box 59, Folder 28)
      - International Labor Press of America, 1949-1952 (Box 59, Folder 29)
      - International League for the Rights of Man, 1956 (Box 59, Folder 30)
      - International Refugee Organization, 1948-1949 (Box 59, Folder 31)
      - International Rescue and Relief Organization, 1949-1949 (Box 59, Folder 32)
      - International Rescue Committee, 1948-1956 (Box 59, Folder 33)
      - International Solidarity Committee, 1948-1949 (Box 59, Folder 34)
      - International Workers Order, 1948-1953 (Box 59, Folder 35)
      - International Workers Order: Background File (Box 59, Folder 36)
      - Italian-American Labor Council, 1948-1952 (Box 59, Folder 37)
      - Jewish Agency for Palestine, 1948-1956 (Box 59, Folder 38)
      - Jewish Agricultural Society, 1954-1955 (Box 59, Folder 39)
      - Jewish Book Council of America, 1951-1956 (Box 59, Folder 40)
      - Jewish Community Council, 1956 (Box 59, Folder 41)
      - Jewish Education Committee, 1951-1953 (Box 59, Folder 42)